# Joshua Bennett

LinkedIn: <u>Joshua Bennett</u>

GitHub: <u>Joshua Bennett (SkimJazz)</u> Address: Cairns, QLD, Australia Email: <u>jb.skimjazz@outlook.com</u>

## **Summary**

With a strong background in Civil Engineering, I bring a unique blend of skills and experiences that can be beneficial to the Software Development industry. My academic journey has equipped me with a solid foundation in problem-solving, attention to detail, and creative thinking. My professional experience has honed my ability to apply engineering techniques, manage projects, and communicate effectively.

## **Projects**

Portfolio TradesEquip Reast API

# **Professional History**

## Nov 2021 - May 2022 Developer (Student) TabLogs Brisbane

- Design UX/UI for application features
- Conducting market research to ensure the application features align with Australian standards.
- Creating custom application manuals aligned with Australian Standards.
- Entering test data and producing CSV test reports for clients.
- Assisting as a technical intermediate between developer and geotechnical engineering clients.

#### Mar 2021 to July 2021 Geotechnical Engineer Soil Surveys Engineers Gold Coast

- Carrying out Engineering testing and Site safety inspections.
- Supervision of geotechnical and environmental drilling programs.
- Producing proposals and final reports.
- Assist administrative, laboratory and engineering teams and project managers by developing a strong rapport with clients during project delivery.

### 2017 to Feb 2021 Geotechnical Laboratory and Site Technician Douglas Partners Gold Coast

- Carry out Quality Control and Quality Assurance laboratory tests on concrete; aggregates, and other construction materials according to various standard procedures (e.g. ASTM, TMR, AS (Australian Standards), RMS).
- Carrying out laboratory tests on soil samples according to various standard procedures, as part of geotechnical investigations.
- Working with and providing support to other Laboratories within Douglas Partners.

- Assist administrative, laboratory and engineering teams and project managers by developing a strong rapport with clients during project delivery.

# **Education and Training**

### Diploma of IT (Web Development) Coder Academy 2022-2024

Skills developed: - Appli

- Application of relevant standards and codes
- Document organization and archiving
- Planning, managing and execution of applications
- Written and oral communication
- Computer Science techniques
- Data Analysis

## Bachelor of Engineering Honors (Civil): Griffith University 2013-2017

Skills developed:

- Application of high level mathematical and statistical analysis techniques.
- Application of engineering techniques, tools, and resources
- Application of relevant standards and codes
- Document organization and archiving
- Planning, managing and execution of projects and reports
- Written and oral communication
- Attention to detail and creative thinking

Referees available on request